A Finding Aid to the Robert Pincus-Witten Papers, 1942-2017, bulk 1962-2005, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Robert Pincus-Witten papers
1942-2017
bulk 1962-2005
Archives of American Art
Pincus-Witten, Robert, 1935-2018
AAA.pincrobe
Archival Resource Key
12.4 Linear feet
The papers of art historian, critic, and curator Robert Pincus-Witten measure 12.4 linear feet and date from 1942-2017. The collection consists of biographical material; color and black and white photographs and negatives; writings by Pincus-Witten; teaching files and printed material; journals; sketches by Pincus-Witten; professional files related to curatorial work; correspondence; artist files maintained by Pincus-Witten; and audiovisual and born digital materials.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Pincus-Witten (1935-2018) was an art historian, educator, critic, and curator in New York, New York.
Born in the Bronx, Pincus-Witten attended PS4, the New York High School of Music and Art, and The Cooper Union. During this time Pincus-Witten met his husband, Leon Hecht, who lived on the same block and was in the same kindergarten class at PS4. He also formed a lifelong friendship with high school classmate and artist, Ray Johnson. Pincus-Witten received a Master of Fine Arts and PhD from the University of Chicago and lived abroad in the late 1950s and early 1960s. Pincus-Witten became interested in art at a very early age and received recognition in the Regional and National Scholastic Art Awards in 1950 and 1952.
While living abroad and finishing his doctorate, Pincus-Witten accepted a teaching position at Queens College, part of the City University of New York (CUNY) network, where he taught art history courses until his retirement in 1991. Coining the term, "postminimalism," Pincus-Witten played a central role in explicating postmodern art as it emerged between 1960 and his death in 2018. He exhaustively documented his daily life on the front lines of the art world as a contributing editor for Artforum for nearly fifty years, including a stint as senior editor from 1973-1974. In addition to his long teaching career at the CUNY, Pincus-Witten worked for Larry Gagosian and Robert Mnuchin, curating exhibitions and writing catalog essays for their galleries. He was the author of several books, including Postminimalism (1977).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1942-circa 2010s (1.00 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1952-2015 (1.60 linear feet, Box 1, 2, 4)
Series 3: Journals, 1958-2015 (3.30 linear feet, Box 3, 12-18)
Series 4: Writing, 1953-2016 (1.50 linear feet, Box 4-5)
Series 5: Artist Files, 1950-2016 (1.60 linear feet, Box 5-7)
Series 6: Professional Files, 1959-2009 (1.50 linear feet, Box 7-8)
Series 7: Teaching Files, circa 1970s-1996 (0.50 linear feet, Box 8-9)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1962-2017 (0.95 linear feet, Box 9-10)
Series 9: Artwork, 1959-1996 (0.25 linear feet, Box 10)
Series 10: Unidentified Born Digital Materials, 1980s-2000s (0.2 linear feet, Box 10)
Scope and Contents
The papers of art historian, critic, and curator Robert Pincus-Witten measure 12.0 linear feet and date from 1942-2017. The collection consists of biographical material; color and black and white photographs and negatives; writings by Pincus-Witten; teaching files and printed material; journals; sketches by Pincus-Witten; professional files related to curatorial work; correspondence; artist files maintained by Pincus-Witten; and audiovisual and born digital materials.
The collection includes biographical material such as passports, address books, calendars, report cards, diplomas, and other academic ephemera; journals that document Pincus-Witten's daily personal and professional activities; drafts of articles, essays and other writings by Pincus-Witten; correspondence with friends and colleagues; teaching files from City University of New York that include lecture notes, slide lists, and student correspondence; research files on artists from the circa 1970s-1996; professional files that document Pincus-Witten's work at Gagosian Gallery and other curatorial activities; and photographs and negatives of family, friends, events and works of art. Also included are audio visual material consisting of two reel-to-reel tape recordings and seventeen sound cassettes documenting panels that featured Pincus-Witten, artist interviews, and Pincus-Witten dictating essays; born digital material including a CD-R from Rose Cabot's "The Marks Project" and 5.25 floppy disk(s) that include Pincus-Witten's writings; pencil, ink, and watercolor sketches and sketchbooks; and printed material consisting of exhibition announcements and invitations, pamphlets, press releases, event programs, newsletters, flyers, and clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
Robert Picus-Witten's journals are access restricted; written permission is required. Contact Reference Services for more information. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated in 2019 by Leon Hecht, Robert Pincus-Witten's husband.
Related Materials
Also found in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Robert Pincus-Witten conducted by Francis M. Naumann, March 23-24, 2016.
Art critics -- New York (State) -- New York; Art historians -- New York (State) -- New York; Educators -- New York (State) -- New York; LGBTQ+; Diaries; Drawings; Interviews; Sound recordings; Postmodernism; Bochner, Mel, 1940-; Hecht, Leon; Hesse, Eva, 1936-1970; Twombly, Cy, 1928-; Gagosian Gallery
- Biographical Material, 1942-circa 2010s; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Box 1
  Scope and Contents
  Materials include report cards, class schedules, diplomas, and other ephemera that document Pincus-Witten's interest in art during his formative years, and his academic career from elementary school through his doctorate. Also included are color and black and white photographs of family, friends, and classmates; headshot proofs taken by Fred Thumhart in 1978; identification documentation including international student IDs and vaccination cards from the late 1950s, United States passports, New York State driver's licenses, and press passes; a 2003 portrait of Pincus-Witten by Martin Summers; notes and letters regarding High School of Music and Art graduation in 1953; a 1991 Queens College retirement certificate; 1950 and 1952 Regional and National Scholastic Art Awards and photographs of works submitted by Pincus-Witten; sketches and portraits drawn by Robert-Pincus Witten in circa 1952; address books filled with business cards, hand written contact information, notes, telephone messages, postcards, letters, photographs, and handwritten addresses on scraps of paper; and a 1942 World War II Ration Book Two.
  - Address Books, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Item 1)
  - Address Books, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Item 2)
  - Address Books, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Item 3)
  - Address Books, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Item 4)
  - Address Books, circa 2000s-circa 2010s; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Item 5)
  - AICA/USA Membership Directory and Business Cards, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Black and White Photographs and Negatives of Robert Pincus-Witten Living Abroad, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Black and White Photograph on Cardboard from Alice Weston, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class Schedules, High School of Music and Art, 1952, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Color Photograph with Allen Ginsberg and a Clipping of Ginsberg's Obituary, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Elementary School and High School Diplomas, 1949, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Handmade New Year Card, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Headshot Proofs Taken by Fred Thumhart, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - High School of Music and Art Notes of Recognition, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - High School of Music and Art Senior Class Ephemera, 1952-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - High School Reunion Materials, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - International Student ID Cards and Vaccination Certificates; New York State Driver Licenses; Press Passes, 1956-1959, 1992-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letter from Seventeen Magazine re Publication Submission, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Martin Summers Portrait of Robert Pincus-Witten, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Medical Benefits Guide and Patient Care Information, 2003-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notes and Letters re High School Graduation, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photograph of Classmate, Mildred Greenwald, circa 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs of Mother [Charlotte Pincus], 1923, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of Tante Anna, Charlotte Pincus, and Robert Pincus-Witten, 1958, 1973, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Photographs with Friends and Family, 1952-1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - P.S.4 Graduating Class Ephemera, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Queens College Retirement Certificate, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Regional and National Scholastic Art Awards and Photographs of Works Submitted, 1950, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Report Cards, High School of Music and Art and PS4, 1948, 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Report Cards, Queens College, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Report Cards, The Cooper Union Art School, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Sketches, Portraits, circa 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Cooper Union Alumni Association Golden Legion Induction Materials, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Cooper Union Diploma, Graduation Program, and Award Letter, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - United States Passports, 1957-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - University of Chicago Diplomas and Graduation Program, 1960, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - WWII War Ration Book Two, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, 1952-2015; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 1.6 Linear feet Box 1, 2, 4
  Correspondence includes letters, post cards, greeting cards, birth announcements, printed emails, and annotated exhibition announcements and invitations from friends, family, artists, galleries, and colleagues. People of note include Mel Boucher, Judy Gantzman, Gary Komarin, David Salle, Sean Scully, and letter from Eleanor Roosevelt to Pincus-Witten's grandmother, "Oma." There are also letters to and from Pincus-Witten's PhD advisor, Joshua C. Taylor, where they discuss Pincus-Witten's thesis and starting his teaching career at Queens College in the 1960s. There are many enclosures in the correspondence files including clippings, sticky notes, research materials related to Alphonse Osbert, color and black and white photographs, photographs of Pincus-Witten and Leon Hecht at events, slides, contracts, sketches, and small works of art. Also included are several postcards and other items that are considered mail art.
  - A, 1985-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - B, 1962-2005. undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Birth Notifications, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Mel Bochner, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Mel Bochner, 1975-2015, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - C, 1964-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Chak, 1993-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Ronald Cohen, 1983-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - D, 1961-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - E, 1987-2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Empty Envelopes, 1983-2015, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - F, 1997-1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - G, 1991-2010, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Judy Glantzman, 1996-1997, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Grandmother (Oma), 1955-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Greeting Cards, 1968-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Greeting Cards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - H, 1963-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Leon Hecht, 1982, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - I, 1968-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, 1981-1999, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - J, 1963-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - K, 1964-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gary Komarin, 1994-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - L, 1962-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - M, 1963-2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Unidentified Correspondents, 1962-1981, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - N, circa 1978-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - O, 1976-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence re Alphonse Osbert, 1963-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence re Alphonse Osbert, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - P, 1971-1990, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Charlotte Pincus (Mother), 1982-1987, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - R, 1964-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - S, 1964-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - David Salle, 1983-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sean Scully, 1992-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Janet Stone (Leonard), 1982-1986, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - T, 1963-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Joshua C. Taylor, 1963-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - U, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - V, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - W, 1983-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Scipio Waller, 1952-1958, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wedding Invitations, 1982-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Wedding Invitations, 1999-2015, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Z, 1964-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Postcards, A, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Postcards, B, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Postcards, C, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Postcards, D, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Postcards, E, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Postcards, F, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Postcards, G, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Postcards, H, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Postcards, I, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Postcards, J, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Postcards, K, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Postcards, L, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Postcards, M, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Postcards, N, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Postcards, O, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Postcards, P, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Postcards, R, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Postcards, S, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Postcards, T, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Postcards, V, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Postcards, Z, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Postcards, Mom, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Postcards, Unidentified Sender, circa 1955-circa 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Journals, 1958-2015; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 3.3 Linear feet Box 3, 12-18
  Conditions Governing Access
  Robert Pincus-Witten's journals are access restricted; written permission is required. Contact Reference Services for more information. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
  Included are Pincus-Witten's personal journals he kept from 1959-1961 while he was living or visiting abroad during graduate school, and from 1971 through 2015. These journals document the daily activities of Pincus-Witten's personal and professional life, most notably his visits to galleries, museums and studios, and encounters with significant figures in the art world. They are filled with annotated scraps of papers noting topics and artists, photographic material, notes, letters, invitations, business cards, clippings, postcards, drawings, event tickets, receipts, annotated cocktail napkins, greeting cards, exhibition announcements and other print material. Excerpts, or entries, from the journals are also found among Pincus-Witten's writings as he published them in a recurring column in Arts magazine from 1976 to 1990.
  - Journal European Stay Summer 1957 and Journal European Stay 1958, 1959 Notebook 1, 10 Oct. 1958-15 Nov. 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Journal European Stay Notebook 2, 17 Nov. 1958-10 April 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Journal European Visit 1958-1959 Continued Notebook 3, 11 April 1959-21 July 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Journal European Sojourn 1958-1959 Continued, 22 July 1959-03 Sept. 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Journal Chicago, Autumn 1959, Winter 1959, 1960, Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Journal Chicago, New York, Paris, New York, Chicago, 11 May 1960-12 Oct. 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 26 Aug. 1970-22 Aug. 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 28 Aug. 1971-09 July 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 15 July 1972-07 May 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 9 May 1973-28 Jan. 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Item 1)
  - Journal, 01 Feb. 1977-01 Jan. 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Item 2)
  - Journal, 08 Jan. 1978-16 Jan. 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Item 3)
  - Journal, 20 Jan. 1979-23 June 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 29 June 1979-25 Dec. 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 01 Jan. 1980-23 Aug. 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Item 1)
  - Journal, 01 Sept. 1980-28 Sept. 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 02 Jan. 1982-31 Jan. 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 01 Feb. 1983-23 Oct. 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Item 2)
  - Journal, 18 Nov. 1983-17 July 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Item 3)
  - Journal, 28 June 1984-22 June 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Item 4)
  - Journal, 01 July 1985-23 July 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Journal, 25 July 1986-29 Nov. 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Item 1)
  - Journal, 14 Dec. 1987-27 Dec. 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Item 1)
  - Journal, 13 Dec. 1988-28 Jan. 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Item 2)
  - Journal, 01 Feb. 1990-28 May 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 04 June 1990-25 Nov. 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Journal, 16 Dec. 1990-16 May 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 08 June 1991-17 Jan. 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 01 March 1992-10 Nov. 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Item 2)
  - Journal, 22 Nov. 1992-20 Sept. 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Item 3)
  - Journal, 22 Sept. 1993-31 Oct. 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Item 4)
  - Journal, 03 Nov. 1994-circa 23 Nov. 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Item 3)
  - Journal, 09 Dec. 1995-07 July 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Item 4)
  - Journal, 27 July 1997-31 Dec. 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Item 5)
  - Journal, 01 Jan. 2001-17 Nov. 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Item 1)
  - Journal, 18 Feb. 2002-25 Nov. 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Item 2)
  - Journal, 01 Dec. 2002-23 April 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Item 3)
  - Journal, 26 April 2004-30 May 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Item 4)
  - Journal, 12 June 2005-29 April 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Item 5)
  - Journal, 05 May 2006-08 June 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Item 1)
  - Journal, 14 June 2007-20 August 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Item 2)
  - Journal, 27 Aug. 2009-20 Sept. 2009; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Item 3)
  - Journal, 25 Sept. 2009-09 May 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Item 4)
  - Journal, 20 June 2011-05 April 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Item 5)
- Writings, 1953-2016; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Box 4-5
  Writing includes annotated calendars and day planners from 1984-2016; typed and handwritten draft essays, articles, lectures, and journal excerpts from 1978-2002; Pincus-Witten's graduate and undergraduate essays and notes, including his thesis proposal and sample chapters; an undated poem he wrote entitled, "The Wit and Wisdom of Larry Gagosian," writings related to political and critical views dated 1973-1975; and three folders of handwritten notes from circa 1969 to the 2000s. Also included are audio recordings on cassette tapes of Pincus-Witten dictating drafts of his writing in the 1980s and 1990s.
  - Annotated Calendars, 1984, 1986-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 1991-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 1999-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 2002-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 2007-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 2013; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Annotated Day Planners, 2014-2016; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Drafts, "A Fly in the Pigment: an Introduction to the Roy Lichtenstein Catalog Raisonńe", circa 2014; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Drafts, Bertha Urdang, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Drafts, Dictation by Robert Pincus-Witten, circa 1980s-circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key; 5 Sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Drafts, "Entries: Salade Nicose", circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Drafts, "Entries: The Price of Everything and the Value of Everything", 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Drafts, "Entries: Third Intermission", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Drafts, "Receding Horizons: Entries from an Eighties Journal", circa 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 4)